Jordan Craig Hornblow

Elwood, Melbourne VIC 3184, Australia

Telephone: (+61) 412 816 666 Email: <u>jordan@jch254.com</u>

Website: jch254.com | linkedin.com/in/jch254

I'm a developer interested in music, productivity and self-improvement. I was born and raised in New Zealand where I spent the first twenty three years of my life learning the ways of the world; I currently live in Melbourne. I love that one can never know too much about technology. There is always an opportunity to continue expanding and applying my knowledge base. This concept of continual improvement is one I have found to be common among all my interests.

I enjoy working across all aspects of product development. I believe that a deeper understanding of the stack allows me to architect higher quality/more robust solutions and diagnose/solve bugs/issues more efficiently. I revel in building applications/systems from the ground up as well as maintaining and enhancing pre-existing systems. I'm currently spending my time with AWS, Node.js and React.

Education

2009 - 2011

University of Canterbury, Christchurch Bachelor of Science (Computer Science)

• I worked on several projects in Java, C, C++, Python and Android. I was part of a year-long, six person software engineering group project developing an Audience Response System. This system allowed university lecturers to 'ask' a class full of students questions and collect/visualise responses from these students in real time. This was done via a Java based web application which lecturers used to 'ask' questions, and an Android application for students to respond to these questions.

2004 - 2008

Timaru Boys High School, Timaru

Employment History

May 2014 - Present

Xero - Melbourne, Australia - Developer

• I am currently working as a developer at Xero in Melbourne. I have worked in several teams across a variety of projects using multiple technologies.

Mar 2012 - Mar 2014

Telogis - Christchurch, NZ - Software Engineer

- I worked at Telogis as a Software Engineer on the enterprise fleet management SaaS 'Telogis
 Fleet'. The majority of my work was in .NET, Javascript and PostgreSQL using an agile
 development process (Kanban) with thorough testing. My role included a leadership aspect which
 involved mentoring new staff members on my team, delegating tasks and reviewing
 code/performance.
- I worked on new feature design/implementation, general bugfixing and optimization of the Telogis
 Fleet backend, along with interprocess communication between many of Telogis' server side
 processes.
- I also worked on the Telogis Fleet UI, redesigning and re-implementing interfaces using the

- Javascript framework Ext JS. I also created several custom Ext JS components which are used in other Telogis products.
- In July/August 2013, I spent five weeks at another Telogis development office in Austin, Texas, USA
 on a developer exchange. The work was at a lower level of the Telogis stack than my usual role and
 included working on Telogis' server side processes. These processes received raw UDP packets
 containing GPS and diagnostic information from vehicles and converted them into a useful and
 standardized format. I also created an integral monitoring service for these processes.

Feb 2011 - Mar 2014 Kiwi Development - Christchurch, NZ - Owner/Software Engineer

- I founded Kiwi Development to further my skills in software and web development and to learn the foundations of running a business. Kiwi Development was accepted into the Microsoft Bizspark program for young tech startups. I undertook both web and software development work for multiple clients using .NET, Ruby on Rails and Javascript.
- One major client was 'The Inzone Experience' where I was in charge of their systems. This role
 involved managing several Windows servers running .NET web applications with SQL Server
 databases. I also maintained and enhanced their main web application which runs on hundreds of
 kiosks throughout NZ to be more efficient and reliable.

Feb 2011 – Oct 2011

University of Canterbury - Christchurch, NZ - Tutor

- I worked at Canterbury University as a tutor for first year computer science and software engineering papers which teach programming skills in Python. I ran labs of up to 50 students. This role involved explanation and understanding of core computer science and software engineering concepts, helping students out when needed and essential people skills.
- I also worked as a tutor for the Pacific Academic Solutions & Success programme, where I tutored Pacific students in computer science and software engineering papers.

Nov 2010 – Feb 2011

HITLab NZ - Christchurch, NZ - Research Intern

 I was awarded a University of Canterbury Summer Scholarship which allowed me to work in the HITLab as a research intern on a project titled "Exploring the use of Mobile Augmented Reality for Navigation". My main responsibility within this project was running user experiments, recording and analysing the data. I also had to learn Android programming skills, and acquire an understanding of mobile augmented reality systems.

Nov 2009 - Feb 2010

Noel Leeming - Timaru, NZ - Salesperson

• During my time at Noel Leeming I worked as a salesperson which involved working with large amounts of customers, processing sales and working with cash.

Achievements

- University of Canterbury Summer Scholarship 2010-2011
- Member of the Golden Key International Honour Society 2009 onwards
- University of Canterbury College of Engineering Computer Science Scholarship 2009
- NZ University Entrance
- NCEA Levels 1, 2, and 3

Hobbies

- Self improvement
- Fitness
- Productivity
- Music
- Photography

References

Simon Cuce Ex-Development Manager - Xero simon@cuce.com.au (+61) 409 667 790 Peter Doake CEO - The Inzone Experience peter@inzone.co.nz (+64) 27 443 9664